

□ (+65) 8158-6831 | **☑** yang0478@ntu.edu.sg | **☆** marsrock.net | **⊙** marsrocky | **□** jianfei-yang-55560386

Research Interests

My research focuses on developing transfer learning algorithms to enhance the generalization of deep learning models. I am interested in tackling the problem of lack of high-quality annotated data confronting various tasks. Revolving this goal, I mainly study the following topics:

- · Machine learning: transfer learning, especially domain adaptation, multi-task learning, few-shot learning
- Computer vision: visual recognition under challenging circumstances (limited annotations and noisy data such as rainy or hazy images)
- Interdisciplinary research: ubiquitous smart sensing based on Internet of Things (IoT), computer-aided structural and earthquake engineering, vision-based identification for animal husbandry, face expression recognition and analysis

Education

Nanyang Technological University

Singapore 2016 - 2020

Ph.D., School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering Supervisor: IEEE Fellow, IFAC Fellow, Prof. Lihua Xie

University of California, Berkeley

California, USA

VISITING SCHOLAR, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCES

2018 - 2019

Sun Yat-sen University

B.S., DEPARTMENT OF DATA AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Guangzhou, China

2012 - 2016

Experience_

Chinese Academy of Science

Beijing, China

COMPUTER VISION ADVISOR

April 2019 - Present

 $\bullet \ \ \text{Offer professional suggestions on developing visual recognition systems and building large-scale database.}$

DJI

Shenzhen, China

VISION ENGINEER INTERN

June 2015 - Sep 2015

• Develop a high-performance yet efficient visual tracking algorithm running in the robots.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2019	Winner, IEEE CVPR 2019 UG2+ Challenge (Zero-shot Detection in Rain)	Long beach, USA
2018	Winner, PEER Hub ImageNet Challenge by Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center	Los Angelos, USA
2018	Winner, ACM ICMI 2018 Emotion Recognition Challenge	Colorado, USA
2018	AAAI Travel grants 2018, AAAI	New Orleans, USA
2017	Winner (1/771), JD Global Data Challenge (Livestock face recognition)	Beijing, China
2017	Winner (1/120), Buildathon of Singapore by Ministry of Education (Singapore)	Singapore
2016	Winner (1/20000), Microsoft Beauty of Programming Challenge by Microsoft Research Asia	Shanghai, China
2015	Intel Prize, HackNTU (IoT Solutions for the developing countries)	Taipei, China
2015	Meritorious Winner, American Mathematical Contest In Modeling	USA

DOMESTIC

2019	Winner (1/617), HUAWEI Cloud Garbage Recognition Challenge	Shanghai
2017	Winner-up (2/782), Microsoft Imagine Cup in China	Shanghai
2016	Winner, China Mobile Internet of Things Hackathons	Guangzhou, China
2015	First Prize, National Mobile Internet Innovation Contest	Beijing, China
2015	First Prize, National Undergraduate IOT Design Contest by Ministry of Education (China)	Wuxi, China
2014	First Prize, Humanoid Robotics Hackathon by ALDEBARAN	Shenzhen, China
2013	Undergraduate First-class Scholarship (5% students), Sun Yat-Sen University	Guangzhou, China

Publications
JOURNAL

JIANFEI YANG, ZHENG LI, LONG CHEN, JUAN ZHA

JOURNAL	
Learning Gestures from WiFi: A Siamese Recurrent Convolutional Architecture	IEEE IoTJ
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Lihua Xie	2018
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
Device-free Occupancy Sensing Platform using WiFi-enabled IoT Devices for Smart Homes	IEEE IOTJ
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie	2018
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
CareFi: Sedentary Behavior Monitoring System via Commodity WiFi Infrastructures	IEEE TVT
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie	2018
IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology (IF=5.34)	
Unsupervised WiFi-enabled IoT Device-User Association for Personalized Locationbased	IEEE IOTJ
Service	
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Costas Spanos	2018
IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IF=9.52)	
Non-intrusive Occupancy Sensing in Commercial Buildings	ENB
Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Jianfei Yang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
Energy and Buildings 2017 (IF=4.50)	
Conference	
Kervolutional Neural Network	CVPR 2019
Chen Wang, Jianfei Yang, Junsong Yuan, Lihua Xie	2019
WiFi and Vision Multimodal Learning for Accurate and Robust Device-Free Human Activity	CVPR-19 Workshop
Recognition	
Han Zou, Jianfei Yang, Hari Prasanna Das,, Costas J Spanos	2019
Machine Learning empowered Occupancy Sensing for Smart Buildings	ICML-19 Climate Change Workshop
Han Zou, Hari Prasanna Das, Jianfei Yang,, Costas J Spanos	2019
Deep Recurrent Multi-instance Learning with Spatio-temporal Features for Engagement	10111110
Intensity Prediction	ICMI-18
Jianfei Yang, Kai Wang, Xiaojiang Peng, Yu Qiao	2018
Consensus Adversarial Domain Adaptation	AAAI-18
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Costas Spanos	2018
Fine-grained Adaptive Location-independent Activity Recognition using Commodity WiFi	IEEE WCNC-17
Jianfei Yang, Han Zou, Hao Jiang, Lihua Xie	2016 - 2020
WiFi-based Human Identification via Convex Tensor Shapelet Learning	AAAI-17
Han Zou, Yuxun Zhou, Jianfei Yang, Lihua Xie, Costas Spanos	2017
Online Visual Tracking via Correlation Filter with Convolutional Networks	IEEE VCIP-16
JIANFEI YANG, ZHENG LI, CHANG-DONG WANG, WEISHI ZHENG	2016
Compressive Perceptual Hashing Tracking with Online Foreground Learning	IEEE ROBIO-15

2015

Patents _____

PCT International Patents

2019	$\textbf{Device-Free Human Identification and Device-Free Gesture Recognition}, \ \texttt{NTU}$	PCT/US19/47049
2019	Unsupervised WiFi-Enabled Device-User Association for Personalized Location-based Service , UCB	PCT/US2019/033782

CHINESE PATENTS

2018	People Engagement Prediction by Facial Expression Recognition, Chinese Academy of Science	TBD
2018	Robot-aided WiFi-based Indoor Localization, personal	TBD

Talks____

2019	Smart Sensing based on IoT and Transfer Learning, Institute of Electronics, Chinese Academy of Sciences	Beijing, China
2018	Multi-task Learning for Structural Engineering, Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center	UCLA, USA
2018	Vision-based Livestock Surveillance for Husbandry and Insurance, National University of Singapore	Singapore
2018	WiFi-based Human Activity Recognition, IEEE WCNC 2018	Barcelona, Spain
2017	Magic Mirror: An IoT and AI based Intelligent Toy, Microsoft	Shanghai, China
2015	Narrator: A Humanoid Robot Presenter with Markup Language, ALDEBARAN	Shenzhen, China
2015	SwordArt: A Real-Time AR Online Game, Huazhong University of Science and Technology	Wuhan, China

Skills____

- Deep learning framework: Pytorch, Keras, Theano, Caffe
- **Programming languages:** C++, Python, MATLAB, Scala, R, Javescript, HTML5